\.M NATH KOVIND GIVES NOD TO 10% QUOTA BIL
ID TO His QUOTA BiLL-OR ELOMOMICALLE wh
WEAKER SECTION IN GENERAL CATEGORY 1
Y  @ PRIME MINISTER NARENDRA MODI TO RE
1 TO RELEASE COMMEMORATIVE COIN ON SIKH ¢
i SIKH GURU GOBIND SINGH TODAY 6 PRESIL
| PRESIDENT PROMULGATES THE MUSLIM WOME
WOMENIPROTECTION OF RIGHTS ON MARRIAGE
NT PROMULGATES THE COMPANIES (AMENDME?
ENDMENT} ORDINANCE, 2019 & PRESIDENT PF
DENT PROMULGATES THE INDIAN MEDICAL COU!
AL COUNCIL (AMENDMENT) ORDINANCE, 2019
2019  g PRIME MINISTER NARENDRA MODIAD
JODI ADDRESSES CONCLUDING SESSION OF BJP'S.
85 NATIONAL CONVENTION IN NEW DELHI
DELHI @ PM: CONGRESS TRYING TO OBSTRUC
IBSTRUCT AYODHYA CASE IN COURT THROUGHT
OUGH ITS LAWYERS @ PM: 16 % QUOTA FOR ‘
‘A FOR YOUTH OF ECONOMICALLY WEAKER SECT
ER SECTIONS WILL INFUSE NEW CONFIDENCE IN B
NCEINNEWINDIA 9 J? ARMS & AMMUNITION
JNITION RECOVERED FROM THESITE @ LOHRI
) LOHRI BEING CELEBRATED IN MOST PARTS OF T
ITS OF THE COUNTRY 9 PRESIDENT GREETS Pl
1EETS PEOPLE ON LOHRI, MAKAR SANKRANTI, PC
\NTI, PONGAL, BHOGALI BIHU, UTTARAYAN AND
iN AND PUSH PARBON
INTERNATIONAL @ FRANCE: 2
4 A eo oeet 4a 3 Se ee en ee go it
1 KILLED IN PARIS BAKERY BLAST: 47 INJURED ः
URED @§ AFGHANISTAN: 5 POLICEMEN KILLEC
| KILLED IN TALIBAN ATTACK ON CHECKPOINT
OINT @ AT LEAST 12 DEAD AFTER NIGERIA O1
FERIA OIL TANKER EXPLOSION 9 U.S. SAYSTH
sAYS TIME FOR NEW GOVERNMENT IN VENEZUEL
रछा ह दर | १5 दे धमकी &+ $उरू लि :
'S NEW SULTAN TENGKU ABDULLAH SHAH, EXPE:
H, EXPECTED TO BEELECTED KING SYRIA: O
YRIA: OVER 600 PEOPLE EVACUATED FROM ISLA |
}M ISLAMIC STATE GROUP'S REMAINING HOLDOL
4OLDOUT @ 19 DEAD iN NORTHWEST CHINA
CHINA COAL MINE ACCIDENT
gS MS DHONI BECOMES FIFTH BATSMAN TO SCC
SCORE MORE THAN 10,060 ODI RUNS FOR INDIA
R INDIA
है >>. ->ज @ WATCH LIVE TELECAS
ELECAST OF ‘KHELO INDIA YOUTH GAMES 2019’ (
; उ019' ON DD SPORTS (TERRESTRIAL & DTH NETV
JI NE NERC OF DL DAORESHSNAER SHUTTLE
99TH TO 20TH JANUARY @ ADMISSIONS 2019
iS 2019 OPEN FOR FULL-TIME COURSES AT FTII PI
T FTI PUNE & SRETI KOLKATA. APPLY GNLINE Al
LINE AT applyadmission.net/jet2019. LAST DATE
‘T DATE FOR APPLYING: 31ST JANUARY 2019—it
519 DD NEWS IS NOW AVAILABLE IN HD ON
HD ON DD FREE DISH AND YOUTUBE; PLEASE SU
ASE SUBSCRIBE TO THE OFFICIAL YOUTUBE CHAI
IBE CHANNEL OF DD NEWS; HTTPS://WWW.YOUT:
¥.YOUTUBE.COM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL @i
_ @ IFFCO YUVA - A UNIQUE JOB PORTAL FOR
AL FOR THE YOUTH BY IFFCO. TO KNOW MORE V
MORE VISIT: www.iffcoyuva.in 9 PARLIAMENT
छनगहरंगजास COMMITTEE ON WELFARE OF OTHE
F OTHER BACKWARD CLASSES 15 EXAMINING THE
ING THE SUBJECT 'RATIONALISATION OF CREAM’
CREAMY LAYER IN EMPLOYMENT FOR OBCs IN SE.
Cs IN SERVICES & POSTS UNDER THE CONTROL 0:
TROL GF GOVT. OF INDIA’. THOSE WILLING TO SU
G TO SUBMIT THEIR VIEWS ON THE SUBJECT MAY
CT MAY SEND WRITTEN MEMORANDUM EITHERT
THER IN ENGLISH OR HINDI TO LOK SABHA SECT
HA SECRETARIAT. DETAILS HAVE BEEN UPLOADE
LOADED ON LOK SABHA SECRETARIAT WEBSITE
fEBSITE DD NEWS IS NOW AVAILABLE IN HD
EIN HD ON DD FREE DISH AND YOUTUBE; PLEAS
; PLEASE SUBSCRIBE TO THE OFFICIAL YOUTUBE |
UTUBE CHANNEL OF एए अगर: नाव: राहिल, सा
YWW.Y OUTUBE.COM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL
CIAL #& MOB VIOLENCE AND LYNCHING IS A Hi
3 §5 A HEINGUS CRIME AND INVITES SERIOUS Cor
US CONSEQUENCES UNDER THELAW 9 MOB
@ MOB VIOLENCE AND LYNCHING [5 A SERIOUS -
=RIOUS CRIMINAL OFFENCE AND INVITES STRING
STRINGENT PUNISHMENT UNDER THELAW थे.
NW  @ DON’T LET GREED PUT YOUR INVESTMEN
-STMENT AT RISK. ISSUED IN PUBLIC INTEREST BY
REST BY IEPF AUTHORITY, VISIT wwwJepf.gov.in
f.gov.in @ EVERY INVESTMENT ENTAILS SOME
.5 SOME LEVEL OF RISKS.GUARANTEED PROFIT is
ROFIT iS A MYTH. ISSUED IN PUBLIC INTEREST BY
tEST BY IEPF AUTHORITY, VISIT www.iepf.gov.in .
.qov.in  @ NEVER MAKE AN INVESTMENT BASE
NT BASED SOLELY ON THE RECOMMENDATION O
TION OF A KNOWN, CELEBRITY OR FACE VALUE.
JALUE. ISSUED IN PUBLIC INTEREST BY IEPF AUT}
PF AUTHORITY, VISIT www.iepf.gov.in © DDN
g DD NEWS iS NOW AVAILABLE IN HD ON DD FR
४ छाए धार एड 2लाए YOUTUBE: PLEASE SUBSCRH
JBSCRIBE TO THE OFFICIAL YOUTUBE CHANNEL (
ANNEL OF DD NEWS; HTTPS://WWW.YOUTUBE.CC
TUBE.COM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL
@ti
अब og राष्ट्रपति राम नाथ कोविन्द ने सामान्य वर्ग at
र्ग के आर्थिक रूप से कमजोर लोगों के लिए $0५ आरक्षण दि
manasa ४ राष्ट्रपति ने मुस्लिम महिला 1
न सहिला [विवाह अधिकार सर क्षण! अध्यादेश, भारतीय आर्य:
ia आयुर्विज्ञान परिषद (संशोघन! अध्यादेश और कंपनी [संश
संशोधन! अध्यादेश को मंजरी दी... ७ प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोट
उमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी गुरू गोबिंद सिंह जी की 35वीं जयंती के मौदं
: मौके पर आज नई दिल्‍ली में स्मारक सिक्का जारी करेंगे
नारी करेंगे... क प्रधानमंत्री नरेंद्र मोदी ने नई Rech a aor
[में भाजपा के राष्ट्रीय अधिवेशन को संबोधित किया. ज पी
छ७ पीएम पिछली यपीए सरकार ने देश को अघकार में घर
| पीएम आर्थिक रूप से कमजोर वर्ग के लोगों के लिए 10 फीर
ए 10 फीसदी आरक्षण नए भारत में नया विश्वास भरेगा
रेगा # जम्म-करमीर कलगाम मुठभेड़ में सरझाबलों ने दो
बलों ने दो आतंकियों को मार मिराया; हथियार और गोला बार
बारूद बरामद छ देश के कई हिस्सों में आज मनाया जार
न मनाया जा रहा है लोहडी का त्यौहार  ४ राष्ट्रपत्ति ने लोह:
ते ने लोहड़ी, मकर संक्रान्ति, भोगली बिहु, पॉंगल, उत्तरायणी .
त्तरायणी और पौध पर्व पर देशवासियों को शुभकामनाएं दी
एए दी क राष्ट्रपति ने गरु गोविन्द सिंह को उनकी जयन्ती
जयन्ती पर श्रद्धांजलि दी, कहा गरु गोविन्द सिंह के कार्य औ'
कार्य और शिक्षाएं हमें आज भी प्रेरणा देती हैं
. gg अमेरिका में सरकारी कामकाज की आशिक बंदी लग
शिक बंदी लगातार 2टवें दिन भी जारी. क फ्रांस: पेरिस बेद
aed घमाके में दो दमकलकर्मियों और एक पर्यटक की मौत
र्यटक की मौत, 47 घायल. # अफगानिस्तान सुरक्षाचौक॑
Randa पर तालिबान के हमले में 5 पुलिसकर्मियों की मौत
की मौत ४ नाइजीरिया: तेल टैंकर घमाके में कम के कम
म के कम 12 की मौत. ४ अमेरिका: वेनेजुएला में नई सरव
नई सरकार के गठन का समय  मलेशिया: तेंगक  aR
ep अब्दुल्ला शाह को सुल्तान चुना नया, शाह बनने की उम्मीद
न में एक हिस्सा गिरने से 19 की मौत
re (of  e feta
सिडनी वनडे: ऑस्ट्रेलिया ने भारत को उब रन से हराया
T क क्रिकेट लोकेश राहुल और हार्दिक vem a ame!
दया की जगह विजय शकर और शुभमन मिल वनडे टीम में शा
न डीडी न्यज पर भारत की पह
रत की पहली सस्कुत समाचार पत्रिका "वारतावली" प्रस्तुत कर
Feld करती है एक अनोखी हिन्दी से सस्कुत अनुवाद प्रतियो
योगिता-, "है प्रीत जहाँ की रीत सदा”, फिल्म-"परब और परि
परब और पश्चिम”, गीतकार- इन्दीवर, संगीतठकार- कल्याण
कल्याणजी-आनन्द्जी, गायक महेन्द्र कपूर। इस गीत के बोल
त के बोल को हिन्दी से संस्कत में अनवाद कर उ१-01-2019 ₹
1-2019 तक 908६ 254५28५50ा1 छाठका#ाा .एएफ्त पर.
0१५ पर भेजें, अनुवाद प्रतियोगिता के परिणाम की घोषणा 26-
घणा 26-01-2019 के "वार्तावली" कार्यक्रम में की जाएगी। '
जाएगी। # संस्कतदार्तापत्रिका 'वार्तावली' प्रस्तीति अद्भर
ति अद्भुतामेकां हिन्दीचलचित्रमीतानां संस्कुतानुवादस्प्ामु1 .
इस्पर्धाम। अस्य गीतस्य . गेयतानुकुल मौलिकानुवाद विधाव <
मत सदा” | चलचित्रम- “परव और पश्चिम” गीतकार:- इन्दीर
र:- इन्ठीवर:1 सड़ातकारीं - कल्याणजी, आनन्दजी चा गायक
चा गायक - महेन्ट्रकपर 1 अस्य गीतस्यानवाद कत्वा 21-01-.
[21-01-2019 feareqd=d DDNEWS4SANSKRIT@GM
{T@GMAIL.COM sfa axe Waaeqi ufalhrarar. Ge
एया: परिणाम: 26-01-2019 तम-दिनाकस्य 'दार्तावली' कार्यद्र
ली' कार्यक्रमे घोषयिष्यते।  # एफटीआईआई, पणे और एर
ह और एसआरएफटीआईइ, कोलकाता म॑ उ019 के पुणकालिक
एकालिक पाठ्यक्रमों म॑ं नामांकन के लिए अनिलाइन आवेदन
| Ha SX- applyadmission.net/jet2019. नामाकन <
नामाकन करने की अंतिम तारीख- 31 जनवरी 20१9 छत
@ ताजा खबरों के लिए १001छ8६ पर हमारा चैनल एम
Waal DD NEWS Watwigd St: HTTPS://WWW.YOU
}W.YOUTUBE.COM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL @
न. छ संस्कुतवातापत्रिका 'वार्तावली' प्रस्तौति अद्भतामेक
पद्धतामेकां हिन्दीचलचित्रमीतानां संस्कुतानवादस्पर्धामा अस्य
मा अस्य गीतस्य . गेयतानकल मौलिकानवाद विधाय यथाशी!
य यथाशीघ्न प्रेचयन्ता गीतम्‌ - "खलबली है खलबली” चलचि
"| चलघित्रमू- “रग दे बसन्ती” गीतकारी- प्रसुन जोशी, नसी
शी, नसीम: चा सड़तकार: - ए.आर.रहमान:, गायका: - नसी
नसीम:,ए.आर.रहमान:.मोहम्मद-असलम: चा। अस्य गीतस्याः
अस्य गीतस्यानवाद कुत्वा 07-01-2019 दिनाकपपर्यन्त 00६
aI DDNEWS4SANSKRIT@GMAIL.COM इति सकते प्रेका
| प्रेचयन्त, प्रतियोगिताया: परिणाम: 12-01-2019 तम-दिनांकर
9 तम-दिनांकस्य 'वार्तावली' कार्यक्रमे घोषयिष्यते। नई!
8 न दिल्‍ली में ड जनवरी से 3 फ़रवरी 2019 के बीच ना
बीच FTI पणे आयोजित x Wel & WEEKEND FILM APP
LM APPRECIATION COURSE  . ताजा खबरों के लि
Ri & fel? YOUTUBE OF SARI dae DD NEWS Gael
5 Vass BY: HTTPS//WWW.YOUTUBE.COM/US
‘OM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL 9 ama Préurat:
वेश को लालच हेतु खतरे म॑ न डाले |EPF AUTHORITY &
अर १ द्वारा जनहित में जारी www.iepf.gov.in सा प्रर
# प्रत्येक निदेश में कुछ ना कुछ जोखिम होता है। गारंटीक
1 गारंटीकत मनाफा एक मिथक है। 1६8 AUTHORITY aRT
ITY द्वारा जनहित में जारी। कक उसूर्म -यु०्भ ता... बा निवेश
का निवेश करते समय सावधान रहें। कभी भी किसी जानने व
| जानने वाले या प्रसिद्ध व्यक्ति के कहने से निवेश न करें1 1६१
करन 2छानएसा १ द्वारा जनहित में जारी। www.iep!
ww.iepf.gov.in
NATIONAL @ PRESIDENT RAM है
' पद NATH KOVIND GIVES NOD TO 10% QUOTA
QUOTA BILL FOR ECONOMICALLY WEAKER SECTI
हि 5६010 IN GENERAL CATEGORY PRIME!
PRIME MINISTER NARENDRA MODI TO RELEASE €
LEASE COMMEMORATIVE COIN ON SIKH GURU G
sURU GOBIND SINGH TODAY PRESIDENT PR
SENT PROMULGATES THE MUSLIM WOMEN(PROT
NIPROTECTION OF RIGHTS ON MARRIAGE) ORDIF
:}ORDINANCE, 2019 @ PRESIDENT PROMULG
}MULGATES THE COMPANIES (AMENDMENT} ORE
iT) ORDINANCE, 2019 @ PRESIDENT PROMULC
ZOMULGATES THE INDIAN MEDICAL COUNCIL (AA
NCIL [AMENDMENT] ORDINANCE, 2619 @ PRIA
@ PRIME MINISTER NARENDRA MODI ADDRESSE
DRESSES CONCLUDING SESSION OF BJP’S NATIOI
_NATIONAL CONVENTION INNEW DELHI 9 PA
@ PM: CONGRESS TRYING TO OBSTRUCT AYOI
“T AYODHYA CASE IN COURT THROUGH ITS LAW
TSLAWYERS 9 PM: 16 % QUOTA FOR YOUTH:
YOUTH OF ECONOMICALLY WEAKER SECTIONS W
TONS WILL INFUSE NEW CONFIDENCE IN NEW INE
(EWINDIA 9 J? ARMS & AMMUNITION RECOV
|JRECOVERED FROMTHESITE @ LOHRIBEING:
BEING CELEBRATED IN MOST PARTS OF THE COU
‘HE COUNTRY @ PRESIDENT GREETS PEOPLE C
FOPLE ON LOHRI, MAKAR SANKRANTI, PONGAL,
INGAL, BHOGALI BIHU, UTTARAYAN AND PUSH P
PUSH PARBON
@ FRANCE: 2  FIREFIC
FIREFIGHTERS, 1 SPANISH TOURIST KILLED IN PA
DIN PARIS BAKERY BLAST: 47 INJURED @ AFL
@ AFGHANISTAN: 5 POLICEMEN KILLED IN TAL
} IN TALIBAN ATTACK ON CHECKPOINT BAT
@ AT LEAST 12 DEAD AFTER NIGERIA OIL TANK
ILTANKER EXPLOSION 9 U.S. SAYS TIME FOR
A @ MALAYSIAN STATE CHOSES NEW SULTAN
SULTAN TENGKU ABDULLAH SHAH, EXPECTED TC
CTEDTOBEELECTED KING #8 SYRIA: OVER 60
VER 600 PEOPLE EVACUATED FROM ISLAMIC ST?
MIC STATE GROUP'S REMAINING HOLDOUT a
JT @ 19 DEAD IN NORTHWEST CHINA COAL NV
@ MS DHONI!
DHONI BECOMES FIFTH BATSMAN TO SCORE MOI
RE MORE THAN 10,000 ODI RUNS FOR INDIA
DIA
है... >>." जे ७ नमामि हा एक फा
शिया गा: 'डिदिसनन्हेर। छल: उस उाध्मन कु का
IN DD SPORTS (TERRESTRIAL & DTH NETWORK Ol
YORK OF DOORDARSHAN} FROM O9TH TO 20TH)
} 20TH JANUARY  @ ADMISSIONS 2019 OPEN F
OPEN FOR FULL-TIME COURSES AT FTH PUNE & 5
UNE & SRFTI KOLKATA. APPLY ONLINE AT applya
| applyadmission.net/jet2019. LAST DATE FOR AF
FOR APPLYING: 31ST JANUARY 2019 9 DDNE
p DD NEWS IS NOW AVAILABLE IN HD ON DD FRE
DD FREE DISH AND YOUTUBE: PLEASE SUBSCRIB
IBSCRIBE TO THE OFFICIAL YOUTUBE CHANNEL O
NNEL OF DD NEWS; HTTPS://WWW.YOUTUBE.CO
UBE.COM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL @ IFFCO Yi
FFCO YUVA - A UNIQUE JOB PORTAL FOR THE YO
THE YOUTH BY IFFCO. TO KNOW MGRE VISIT: ww
SIT: www.iffcoyuva.in © PARLIAMENTARY CO
ARY COMMITTEE ON WELFARE OF OTHER BACKY
} BACKWARD CLASSES IS EXAMINING THE SUBJEC
| SUBJECT ‘RATIONALISATION OF CREAMY LAYER
Y LAYER IN EMPLOYMENT FOR OBCs IN SERVICES
RVICES & POSTS UNDER THE CONTROL OF GOVT.
F GOVT. OF INDIA’. THOSE WILLING TO SUBMIT TI
IBMIT THEIR VIEWS ON THE SUBJECT MAY SEND\
' पाए WRITTEN MEMORANDUM EITHER IN ENGL
N ENGLISH OR HINDI TO LOK SABHA SECRETARIA
RETARIAT. DETAILS HAVE BEEN UPLOADED ON Lt
DON LOK SABHA SECRETARIAT WEBSITE @D
@ DD NEWS [5S NOW AVAILABLE INHD ON DD
}ON DD FREE DISH AND YOUTUBE; PLEASE SUBS:
E SUBSCRIBE TO THE OFFICIAL YOUTUBE CHANN:
CHANNEL OF DD NEWS; HTTPS://WWW.YOUTUBE
DUTUBE.COM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIAL © MOE
@® MOB VIOLENCE AND LYNCHING IS A HEINOUS
EINOUS CRIME AND INVITES SERIOUS CONSEQUE
NSEQUENCES UNDER THELAW @ MOB VIOLEF
, VIOLENCE AND LYNCHING I5 A SERIOUS CRIMIN.
CRIMINAL OFFENCE AND INVITES STRINGENT PUI
ENT PUNISHMENT UNDER THELAW 9 DON'TI
DON’T LET GREED PUT YOUR INVESTMENT AT Ri
T AT RISK. ISSUED IN PUBLIC INTEREST BY IEPFA
Y IEPF AUTHORITY, VISIT wwwiiepif.gov.in के E
@ EVERY INVESTMENT ENTAILS SOME LEVEL .
= LEVEL OF RISKS.GUARANTEED PROFIT 15 A MYT
; A MYTH. ISSUED IN PUBLIC INTEREST BY IEPF AL
iEPF AUTHORITY, VISIT www.iepi.cov.in  @ NI
@ NEVER MAKE AN INVESTMENT BASED SOLE
-D SOLELY ON THE RECOMMENDATION OF A KNC
= A KNOWN, CELEBRITY OR FACE VALUE. ISSUED!
SSUED IN PUBLIC INTEREST BY IEPF AUTHORITY,
IGRITY, VISIT www.iepf.gov.in 8 DD NEWSIS |
EWS IS NOW AVAILABLE IN HD ON DD FREE DISH
EE DISH AND YOUTUBE; PLEASE SUBSCRIBE TO TI
3E TO THE OFFICIAL YOUTUBE CHANNEL OF DDN
JF DD NEWS; HTTPS://WWW.YOUTUBE.COM/USEI
IM/USER/DDNEWSOFFICIALs